




  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
		
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Introduction to Trees :: CC 315 Textbook</title>
    <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc315/ii-trees/2-introduction-trees/</link>
    <description>Welcome! This page is the main page for Introduction to Trees</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 16:12:13 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc315/ii-trees/2-introduction-trees/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc315/ii-trees/2-introduction-trees/1-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc315/ii-trees/2-introduction-trees/1-introduction/</guid>
      <description>Video Materials&#xA;For the next data structure in the course, we will cover trees, which are used to show hierarchical data. Trees can have many shapes and sizes and there is a wide variety of data that can be organized using them. Real world data that is appropriate for trees can include: family trees, management structures, file systems, biological classifications, anatomical structures and much more.&#xA;We can look at an example of a tree and the relationships they can show.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>General Terms</title>
      <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc315/ii-trees/2-introduction-trees/2-general-terms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc315/ii-trees/2-introduction-trees/2-general-terms/</guid>
      <description>Video Materials&#xA;To get ourselves comfortable in working with trees, we will outline some standard vocabulary. Throughout this section, we will use the following tree as a guiding example for visualizing the definitions.&#xA;Definitions Node - the general term for a structure which contains an item, such as a character or even another data structure. Edge - the connection between two nodes. In a tree, the edge will be pointing in a downward direction.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Makes a Tree a Tree</title>
      <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc315/ii-trees/2-introduction-trees/3-what-makes-trees/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc315/ii-trees/2-introduction-trees/3-what-makes-trees/</guid>
      <description>Video Materials&#xA;Trees can come in many shapes and sizes. There are, however some constraints to making a valid tree.&#xA;A tree has a single root A child has exactly one parent A tree is fully connected (IE a single tree) A tree has no cycles (IE no loops) Valid Trees Any combination of the following represents a valid tree:&#xA;A tree with a single node; just a root, A tree where each node has a single child, or A tree where nodes have many children.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MyTree I</title>
      <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc315/ii-trees/2-introduction-trees/4-uml/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc315/ii-trees/2-introduction-trees/4-uml/</guid>
      <description>Video Materials&#xA;Along with understanding how trees work, we want to also be able to implement a tree of our own. We will now outline key components of a tree class.&#xA;MyTree Recall that trees are defined recursively so we can build them from the leaves up where each leaf is a tree itself. Each tree will have three properties: the item it contains as an object, its parent node of type MyTree, and its children as a list of MyTrees.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Summary</title>
      <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc315/ii-trees/2-introduction-trees/5-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc315/ii-trees/2-introduction-trees/5-summary/</guid>
      <description>In this module we have introduce vocabulary related to trees and what makes a tree a tree. To recap, we have introduced the following:&#xA;Child - a node with an edge that connects to another node closer to the root. Degree Degree of a node - the number of children a node has. The degree of a leaf is zero. Degree of a tree - the number of children the root of the tree has.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>